## Nicholas G. McMullen

Certified Total Rewards & Human Resources Professional
Phoenix, AZ, USA
e: nicholasgmcmullen@gmail.com
w: nickmcmullen.github.io
s: linkedin.com/in/nicholas-mcmullen

# Summary

Analytically-inclined, people-oriented HR practitioner with experience supporting executives and front-line teams as a strategic partner. Skilled in rewards design and management, people analytics, human resources operations, and onboarding. Experience implementing, integrating, and managing a variety of HR technology solutions, managing rewards programs, and leading people-people teams.

# **Employment**

#### **Compensation and People Analytics Lead**

January 2022 - Present

RStudio PBC

Boston, MA, USA

- Lead all aspects of RStudio's compensation operations, administration, and design including base salary, short-term incentive (STI), long-term incentive (LTI)
- Assist in the analysis and design of executive compensation programs and incentives
- Participate in salary surveys, benchmark jobs to align with compensation philosophy
- Manage cadenced departmental compensation reviews with executives
- Approve compensation for all external job offers, promotions, and internal transfers
- Build, automate dashboards using R/RStudio/shiny to provide automated, people-related insights to executives
- Configure HR systems to meet company needs and liaise with IT to ensure accurate, secure transfer of data between systems

#### **People Operations Partner**

January 2021 - January 2022

RStudio PBC

Boston, MA, USA

- Built career framework and aligned to salary structures for engineering department
- Conducted job analysis and market pricing of all company jobs
- Assisted in the implementation and company-wide rollout of new HRIS
- Acted as the initial point of contact for employee relations issues
- Trained and coached small groups of managers on effective management practices

#### **Senior Specialist Total Rewards Content**

September 2020 - January 2021

WorldatWork

Scottsdale, AZ, USA

Delivered a preliminary People Analytics practice strategy to association leadership

- Conducted competitive market research in the people analytics education market
- Advised practice leaders on trends, opportunities, and threats in total rewards

### Manager People Systems and Analytics

January 2020 - September 2020

Alliance Residential Company

Phoenix, AZ, USA

- Oversaw operation of all human resources information systems including HRIS (UltiPro), ATS (iCIMS), Compensation (Salary.com), and LMS (Fuse LXP)
- Led implementation of new organizational corporate social responsibility platform
- Conducted job analysis and evaluation of all company jobs
- Administered Quarterly Incentive Program, including building code-based distribution and audit capabilities
- Evaluated effectiveness of HR programs and field performance using R and RStudio and presented findings to executives

### **Manager Talent Analytics and Operations**

May 2018 - January 2020

Alliance Residential Company

Phoenix, AZ, USA

- Oversaw operation of human resources information systems including ATS (iCIMS),
   Compensation (Salary.com), and LMS (Cornerstone OnDemand & Fuse LXP)
- Led implementation of Fuse LXP and company-wide conversion from Cornerstone OnDemand LMS
- Managed Talent Coordinator team responsible for pre-hire onboarding tasks and workflows including offer letters, compliance, and queuing profiles for import to HRIS
- Automated recruiting billback process, including integrating data sources from CRM, ATS, and HRIS and utilizing open source R tools, saving 30+ hours of manual work per month
- Developed suite of automated Tableau dashboards to support monthly reporting needs of Talent executive team

#### **Learning and Development Intern**

June 2017 - August 2017

Alliance Residential Company

Phoenix, AZ, USA

- Assisted with administration and management of Cornerstone OnDemand LMS
- Built and distributed reports required by the field Learning and Development team
- Analyzed training program data for business impact and presented results to executive team

## Education

B.A. magna cum laude, Applied Mathematics and Statistics

August 2014 - May 2018

Macalester College St. Paul, MN, USA

## Certifications

**Certified Compensation Professional (CCP)** 

WorldatWork .

Expires November 2023

**Global Remuneration Professional (GRP)** 

WorldatWork

Expires November 2023

**Professional in Human Resources (PHR)** 

Human Resources Certification Institute (HRCI)

Expires February 2024

**Tableau Desktop 2019 Certified Associate (expired)** 

Tableau Software

**Expired October 2021** 

### Skills

- Base pay design and administration
- Job analysis, documentation, and evaluation
- Incentive compensation program management
- HRIS integration and administration
- ATS implementation, administration
- LMS implementation, administration
- Talent onboarding process development and management
- People program analysis and evaluation
- Data cleaning and manipulation
- Process improvement, design, and automation
- People team management

# Software Experience

- R programming
- Shiny app development
- RStudio IDE
- BambooHR HRIS
- Greenhouse.io ATS
- Culture Amp
- Salary.com CompAnalyst
- UltiPro HRIS (UKG)
- iCIMS ATS
- Fuse LXP
- Cornerstone OnDemand LMS
- Qualtrics